<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Parisa's Blog - Deep Learning</title><link href="http://ParisaGY.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ParisaGY.github.io/feeds/deep-learning.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ParisaGY.github.io/</id><updated>2017-01-14T01:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Deep Learning</title><link href="http://ParisaGY.github.io/deep-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-14T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-14T01:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>ParisaGY</name></author><id>tag:parisagy.github.io,2017-01-14:/deep-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning
One of the original objectives of machine learning was to allow computer systems model our world accurate 
enough so that it can be called intelligence. 
In order to do so, most of current research in machine learning tend to collect a large quantity of information 
for computer systems …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning
One of the original objectives of machine learning was to allow computer systems model our world accurate 
enough so that it can be called intelligence. 
In order to do so, most of current research in machine learning tend to collect a large quantity of information 
for computer systems to improve learning algorithms; the challenges of artificial intelligence, however, still remain. 
Deep Learning, also known as deep structured learning, is a new branch in machine learning research introduced to move 
machine learning closer to one of its original goals, artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years, building a machine-learning system needed careful engineering and substantial domain 
expertise to design a feature extractor.&lt;br&gt;
Feature extractor transforms raw data into a suitable internal representation or feature vector 
for the learning system. Using the set of extracted features, the next subsystem, often a classifier, 
can detect or classify patterns in the input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning algorithms are proposed to be fed with raw data and then provide 
automated discovery and extraction of complex data representations (features) 
that are required for detection or classification. Such algorithms develop a layered, 
hierarchical architecture of learning and representing data, where higher-level (more abstract) 
features are defined in terms of lower-level (less abstract) features. These levels of representation are 
obtained by creating simple but non-linear modules that each transform the representation at one level (starting with the 
raw input) into a representation at a higher, slightly more abstract level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References:
-        Bengio, Yoshua. "Learning deep architectures for AI." Foundations and trends® in Machine Learning 2.1 (2009): 1-127.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LeCun, Yann, Yoshua Bengio, and Geoffrey Hinton. "Deep learning." Nature 521.7553 (2015): 436-444.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Najafabadi, Maryam M., et al. "Deep learning applications and challenges in big data analytics." Journal of Big Data 2.1 (2015): 1.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>