<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Parisa's Blog - Graph Database</title><link href="http://ParisaGY.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ParisaGY.github.io/feeds/graph-database.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ParisaGY.github.io/</id><updated>2017-01-07T01:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Graph Database</title><link href="http://ParisaGY.github.io/graph-database.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-07T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-07T01:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>ParisaGY</name></author><id>tag:parisagy.github.io,2017-01-07:/graph-database.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Graph Database in Data Science
Relational databases have been used in software applications for the last three decades. 
Virtually all of these database systems use SQL (Structured Query Language) for querying and maintaining the database. 
They store highly structured data in tables using predefined columns of certain types and many …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Graph Database in Data Science
Relational databases have been used in software applications for the last three decades. 
Virtually all of these database systems use SQL (Structured Query Language) for querying and maintaining the database. 
They store highly structured data in tables using predefined columns of certain types and many rows of the same type of information. 
Relational databases require developers to strictly structure the data used in their applications. 
In relational databases, references to rows and tables are indicated by key attributes and via foreign-key columns. 
This is compute- and memory-intensive and have an exponential cost for many-to-many relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graph database uses graph structures for semantic queries with nodes, edges and properties to store and represent data. 
The relationships allow data to be linked together directly, and in many cases retrieved with a simple query. 
DataStax and Neo4j are two examples of graph databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In data science, analyzing data is the key operation to learn a model tied to a particular representation of data. 
For example, graph database can be used in natural processing language, deep learning text classification, or recommender system development. 
Graph databases provide an efficient storage and also and traversal of information about relationships. 
Hence, graphs can be the input or the output of a machine learning processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References:
-        Wikipedia contributors. "Relational database." Wikipedia, The Free Encyclopedia. Wikipedia, The Free Encyclopedia, 19 Jan. 2017. Web. 8 Feb. 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neo4j, “From Relational to Neo4j,” last access to: “https://neo4j.com/developer/graph-db-vs-rdbms,” Feb 8, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia contributors. "Graph database." Wikipedia, The Free Encyclopedia. Wikipedia, The Free Encyclopedia, 31 Jan. 2017. Web. 8 Feb. 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neo4j, “The next wave of disruption: Graph-based machine learning,” last access to: “https://neo4j.com/news/next-wave-disruption-graph-based-machine-learning/,” Feb 8, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry></feed>